Finding Aid for Daughters of the American Revolution, Philip Livingston Chapter (Howell, Mich.) Records, 1908-2009
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Daughters of the American Revolution, Philip Livingston Chapter (Howell, Mich.) Records 1908-2009
Daughters of the American Revolution. Philip Livingston Chapter (Howell, Mich.)
3 oversize volumes
7 linear feet
2011103 Be.1 2
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The records were the gift of the chapter (donor no. 10605 ) and came from Karen P. McNally in several accessions. Additional material came from Howell Carnegie District Library (donor no. 1284 ) in 2013.
Periodic additions to the records are expected.
The record group is open to research.
The Philip Livingston Chapter of the Daughters of the American Revolution was established in Howell, Michigan in 1908. In 2008, the chapter, still flourishing, celebrated its 100th anniversary.
The records of the Philip Livingston Chapter of the Daughters of the American Revolution consist of scrapbooks of clippings and albums of photographs, yearbooks, award citations, and newspaper articles. Other records include historian’s records, secretary’s minute books, treasurer’s records, chapter reports and awards, collected cemetery records of Livingston County, and yearbooks.
Subjects:
Daughters of the American Revolution. Philip Livingston Chapter (Howell, Mich.); Howell (Mich.); Patriotic societies--Michigan--Howell.; Women--Michigan--Howell--Societies and clubs.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Scrapbooks / Albums
  - Scrapbook 1936-1939 (Box 1)
    (and earlier)
  - Scrapbook 1948-1949 (Box 1)
  - Scrapbook 1949-1950 (Box 1)
    (include photographs)
  - Scrapbook 1951-1952 (Box 1)
  - Scrapbook 1950-1953 (Box 1)
    (compiled by Mrs. Jacob Eager)
  - Scrapbook 1953-1958 (Box 1)
  - Scrapbook, Sixty-first Continental Congress 1952 (Box 1)
    (compiled by Sadie Hicks)
  - Scrapbook 1966-1984 (Box 1)
    (Historian's Record)
  - Scrapbooks / Photograph albums
    - 1966-1995 (Box 2)
    - 1984-1990 (Box 2)
    - 1990-1991 (Box 2)
    - 1999 (Box 2)
    - 1988-1999 (Volume 1)
      (include photographs, programs, award certificates, etc.)
    - 1992-1997 (Volume 2)
    - 2000-2002 (Box 3)
    - 2001 (Box 3)
      (compiled by Janet Rohrabacher)
    - 2002-2007 (Box 3)
    - 2007-2008 (Box 3)
    - Loose items from scrapbooks and albums (Box 3)
    - Album commemorating 100th anniversary of the chapter 2008 (Volume 3)
- Other records
  - American Heritage (Box 4)
    - A Manuscript Cookbook (Box 4)
    - Brave Deed, The (Box 4)
    - Camping in 1920 (Box 4)
    - Cutter Collection, The (Box 4)
    - Flute, The (Box 4)
    - Gold Necklace, The (Box 4)
    - Mother Goose Book, The (Box 4)
    - My Heritage Silver Collection (Box 4)
    - Pioneer, The (Box 4)
      (poem)
    - Polly and the Shoemaker (Box 4)
  - Anniversary
    - 50th (Box 4)
    - 56th (Box 4)
    - 100th (Box 4)
  - Awards, State and National
    - 2000 (Box 4)
    - 2001 (Box 4)
    - 2002 (Box 4)
    - 2003 (Box 4)
    - 2004 (Box 4)
    - 2005 (Box 4)
    - 2006 (Box 4)
    - 2009 (Box 4)
  - Bible and Family Records 2004 (Box 4)
  - Bi-Centennial Commemoration (Box 4)
  - Cemetery Records
    - Index (Box 4)
    - Volume 1, Livingston County (Box 4)
    - Volume 2, Livingston County (Box 4)
    - Volume 3, Livingston County (Box 4)
    - Brighton
      - Cemetery Records (Box 4)
      - Old City Cemetery (Box 4)
    - Brighton Township
      - Pleasant Valley/Beach (Box 4)
      - Woodland Cemetery (Box 4)
    - Cohoctah Township
      - Boutell/Jones Cemetery (Box 4)
      - Sandford Cemetery (Box 4)
    - Conway Township
      - Benjamin Cemetery (Box 4)
      - Benjamin Cemetery manuscript (Box 4)
      - Coughran Cemetery (Box 4)
    - Deerfield Township
      - General (Box 4)
      - Deer Creek Cemetery (Box 4)
      - Deerfield Center/Sharp Cemetery (Box 4)
      - St. Augustine Catholic (Box 4)
    - Genoa Township
      - Chilson Cemetery (Box 4)
      - Kelley Cemetery/Brighton Twp., Bird Cemetery (Box 4)
      - Lutheran Cemetery (Box 4)
    - Green Oak Township
      - Holden Cemetery (Box 4)
      - Union Burying Ground (Box 4)
    - Hamburg Township
      - Hamburg, Village (Box 4)
      - North Hamburg Cemetery (Box 4)
    - Handy Township, Coffy Cemetery (Box 4)
    - Hartland Township
      - Hartland Village (Box 4)
      - Hodge/Hart (Box 4)
      - Old St. Mary's (Box 4)
      - Parshallville (Box 4)
      - Smith-Griswold (Box 4)
  - Cemetery Records (cont.)
    - Marion Township
      - Drew Cemetery (Box 4)
      - Gilkes Cemetery (Box 4)
      - Green Cemetery (Box 4)
    - Oceola Township
      - Kellogg Cemetery (Box 4)
      - Riddle Cemetery (Box 4)
      - St. John's Catholic (Box 4)
      - Van Keuren Cemetery (Box 4)
    - Pinckney Catholic Cemetery (Box 4)
    - Putnam Township, Sprout (Box 4)
    - Tyrone Township
      - Clough Cemetery (Box 4)
      - Colwell Cemetery (Box 4)
      - Gardner Cemetery (Box 4)
    - Unadilla Township, Williamsville Cemetery (Box 4)
  - Chapter Reports
    - 1921-1925 (Box 4)
    - 1926-1930 (Box 4)
    - 1931-1935 (Box 4)
    - 1936-1940 (Box 4)
    - 1963-1966 (Box 4)
    - 1973-1975 (Box 4)
    - 1982-1986 (Box 4)
    - 1986-1990 (Box 4)
    - 1990-1994 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence
    - 1925-1930 undated (Box 4)
      [French Orphan]
    - 1966-1969 (Box 4)
  - Genealogical Records Report, Benjamin Batcheler Family (Box 5)
  - Historian Records
    - 1908-1914 (Box 5)
    - 1927-1942 (Box 5)
    - 1942-1952 (Box 5)
    - 1952-1966 (Box 5)
    - 1966-1984 (Box 1)
  - Howell Historical Museum (Box 6)
    - Birdseye View, Committee Reports, Donations (Box 6)
    - History of (Box 6)
    - List Books 1960, 1968-1969 (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous Loose Papers from Museum Book #1 (Box 6)
    - Origin of Museum, Paper on (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous, 3 folders (Box 6)
  - News clippings
    - 1919-1937 (Box 6)
    - 1960-1969 (Box 6)
    - 1970-2011 (Box 6)
  - Notebooks (Box 6)
  - Obituaries
    - 1980-2010 (Box 6)
    - 1996 (Box 6)
  - Photograph
    - 40th Anniversary 1948 (Box 6)
    - 50th Anniversary 1958 (Box 6)
    - Group at Browne's 1932 (Box 6)
    - Historian Book 1952-1966 (Box 6)
    - Lee, Alice 1921 (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous 1924, 1958 undated (Box 6)
    - Stowe, Kate 1920 Organizing Regent (Box 6)
    - Strick, Richard, Good Citizen 2001 (Box 6)
    - Thomas, Sara, Conservation Medal Recipient 2001 (Box 6)
  - Postcards (Box 6)
  - Presentation, Good Citizens March 7, 1972 (Box 6)
  - Printed
    - 50th State Conference 1950 (Box 6)
    - Cookbook, Celebrating 100 years (Box 6)
    - DAR Schools (Box 6)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 6)
    - Rituals (Box 6)
  - Program
    - Abraham Lincoln and the Constitution (Box 6)
    - Book Review, The Houses in Between (Box 6)
    - Books (Box 6)
    - Christmas (Box 6)
    - Colonial Art (Box 6)
    - Daguerreotype Cases (Box 6)
    - DAR Library, It's Place in Patriotism & Service (Box 6)
    - DAR Museum (Box 6)
    - Dolls (Box 6)
    - Heraldry (Box 6)
    - Historical Societies Past and Present (Box 6)
    - How Chapters Got Their Names (Box 6)
    - I Remember Christmas (Box 6)
    - Indians (Box 6)
    - Livingston County Lore (Box 6)
    - Medicine in Colonial Days (Box 6)
    - Old Glass (Box 6)
    - Post War Peace Plans (Box 6)
    - Romance of Stamps (Box 6)
    - Romances of the Revolution (Box 6)
    - What DAR Does (Box 6)
    - The White House (Box 6)
  - Regents, Miscellaneous (Box 6)
  - Secretary's Records, Minutes (Box 7)
    - 1908-1913 (Box 7)
    - 1913-1917 (Box 7)
    - 1917-1920 (Box 7)
    - 1920-1923 (Box 7)
    - 1923-1926 (Box 7)
    - 1926-1935 (Box 7)
    - 1935-1950, 2 volumes (Box 7)
    - 1950-1979, 3 volumes (Box 7)
    - 1979-2007, 2 volumes (Box 7)
  - Treasurer's Records
    - Finance Journal
      - 1927-1936 (Box 7)
      - 1936-1947 (Box 7)
      - 1947, 1951-1952, 1960-1962 (Box 7)
      - 1977-1993 (Box 7)
    - Financial Annual Reports & Remittances to State & National Projects 1975-2005 (Box 7)
  - Voter Registration List 1882-1890 (Box 7)
  - Yearbooks 1965-2000 scattered (Box 7)
Related Material
The records of the Daughters of the American Revolution of Michigan, also available at the library, include yearbooks and other collected materials of the Philip Livingston Chapter.